William Montooth-Keating

Santa Barbara, CA montooth-keating@ucsb.edu 530-760-8743

Graduate from UC Santa Barbara with a B.S. in Biopsychology and a positive, easygoing personality. Now training to be a full-stack web developer through the UC Davis Web Development Boot Camp. Experienced in customer service, data management, fundraising, and online software for website design and organizational applications. Particularly skilled at managing large groups and handling multiple projects simultaneously, and quick to adapt to new software and technology.

Work Experience

Research Assistant

Human Behavioral Endocrinology Lab - Santa Barbara, CA September 2019 to June 2020

Attended and led lab discussions about research in the field.

Data entry and management of sensitive subject information and samples.

Closed the lab at the end of the day, ensured that samples were properly stored, and verified information from the day's experiments.

Prepared literature reviews upcoming studies and presented the information to other lab members.

Research Assistant

University of California - Santa Barbara, CA January 2019 to March 2020

Ran human subjects through experiments in visual search and attention tasks.

Used advanced eye-tracking technology and MatLab code.

Assisted the graduate students in pilot studies.

Attended lab meetings on coding, neural networks, and signal detection theory.

Peer Mentor

University of California - Santa Barbara, CA June 2019 to December 2019

Santa Barbara, California

Attended a ten week class on peer mentoring and advising with a focus on mentoring those of diverse backgrounds.

Met with department faculty to create a plan for a course to be offered to transfer students in the psychology department, as well as plan the transfer orientation.

Worked closely with a faculty advisor and a group of fellow peer mentors.

Assigned five mentees, mentored them through the educational and social transition to UCSB.

Caterer

University of California - Santa Barbara, CA July 2019 to September 2019

Prepared, transported, and served food and drinks to a wide variety of UC Santa Barbara events.

Worked with a large team of managers, caterers, and chefs to ensure a successful work environment. Maintained a clean working environment at all times.

Community Outreach, Volunteer, and Feline Medical Coordinator

Yolo County SPCA - Davis, CA August 2015 to August 2018

Community Outreach Coordinator

- Wrote content for newsletters, social media pages, and informational packets.
- Organized and supervised events at local schools, retirement communities, and businesses.
- Created and distributed fundraising materials.
- Attended events as a representative of the Yolo County SPCA and made new contacts with possible donors.
- Updated and maintained the membership and donor database on a consistent basis.

Volunteer Coordinator

- Recruited and trained up to 50 new volunteers each month on volunteer program goals and objectives.
- Scheduled and supervised volunteers of all ages at adoption and community outreach events.
- Streamlined volunteer paperwork by implementing an online format with multiple database integrations.
- Wrote, designed, and distributed a weekly eNewsletter to more than two thousand subscribed volunteers
- Provided volunteer opportunities to disabled individuals by matching individual skills and competencies.

Feline Medical Coordinator

- Administered vaccinations, microchips, and various medications to approximately 60 animals each month.
- Trained interns and foster homes on routine medical care and vaccinations.
- Updated and maintained database of veterinary records and medical profiles.
- Communicated with foster homes regarding medical status and treatments for foster animals.

Spay/Neuter Coordinator

- Managed and operated a low-cost spay/neuter transport program for low-income residents of Yolo County.
- Informed owners about animal status and necessary post-operative care.
- Accommodated special needs or disabled members of the community.

Education

Certificate (In Progress) in Full-Stack Web Development

UC Davis Professional and Continuing Education - Davis, CA

December 2020 to Present

Bachelor's in Biopsychology

University of California - Santa Barbara, CA August 2018 to June 2020

Skills

- Web Design
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Research

Awards

UC Santa Barbara Highest Honors

June 2020

Awarded to students in the top 2.5% of GPAs.

Exceptional Academic Achievement Award

June 2020

Awarded to students who have completed at least 36 upper-division units in the Psychological and Brain Sciences Department with a GPA of at least 3.9.

Chairperson's Award

June 2020

Awarded to students who have provided outstanding service to the Psychological and Brain Sciences Department.

Sacramento City College Highest Honors

June 2020

Awarded to students with a GPA of at least 3.5.